# MATTHEW J. SAURO

Chicago, IL • mjsauro@gmail.com• (401) 864-2261 • mjsauro.github.io • github.com/mjsauro

#### WEB DEVELOPER

Full-stack developer with hands-on experience in many facets of web development that involve web forms, interactive databases, encrypted data access, and data security. Demonstrated proficiency in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, AngularJS, NET and C#. Knowledgeable in creating a versatile ecommerce application that includes real-time inventory updates for customer ordering pages. Capable of carrying out multiple projects in a deadline-driven environment.

## Technical Skills

Programming Languages
Web Technologies

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES 5), Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS, C# ASP.NET MVC 5, Entity Framework, Web APIs, Microsoft Azure

/Frameworks

Databases T-SQL

Tools/Methodologies Visual Studio 2017, SQL Server Management Studios

Software GitHub, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, and PowerPoint), Google Developer

Tools

# DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS (AVAILABLE ON GITHUB)

# Library Card Catalog

• Developed a .NET Console Application to easily track & retrieve books in a library. Used **serialization** to save data to an **XML** file.

# Amazon Sign In Page Quiz

• Rebuilt and styled the Amazon Login Page using **HTML** and **CSS** based on a visual asset.

# Weather Application

• Developed a **Single Page Web Application** using **JavaScript**, **HTML**, **CSS** and **jQuery**. Retrieved weather information using the Yahoo Weather **API**. Employed a search functionality to display weather by city and/or state, and the application will detect your location.

## E-Commerce Application

• A fully functional e-commerce site using **NET MVC** and **Entity Framework.** Products and customers are added via **SQL** database and payments are processed through the **Braintree Payments API**. Other languages include **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **Razor**, and **Bootstrap**.

### A Tribute to Chris Cornell

• A simple site giving tribute to singer, Chris Cornell. This project features HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and AngularJS.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

# FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Coding Temple, Chicago, IL

July 2017 - Present

Part of a development team involve in developing various projects for clients including E-commerce Application, Weather Application and Library Card Catalog Application. Effectively collaborates with the team to provide support, and resolve issues in the timely delivery of the project deliverables. Regularly determines new ways of improving existing environment discovering ways to implement new technology into existing infrastructure.

- Worked with senior developers in building an e-commerce website from the front-end to back-end functionalities
- Completes detailed programming to create clean interfaces
- Designed the project wireframe for the website layout

- Implemented HTML and CSS to enhance design and display content
- Utilized bootstrap to create responsive and quick web design for all devices and browsers
- Designed the project wireframe and layout for all of the pages in the e-commerce application
- Involved in UI design and development using ASP.NET MVC, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Angular JS
- Developed structure and layout with HTML5 and CSS3 in Visual Studio 2017
- Utilized bootstrap to create responsive and quick web design for all devices and browser
- Created a Web API to allow my website to access information stored in my database
- Used LINQ and Entity Framework to exchange data between web applications and database objects

ENVIRONMENT: ASP.NET MVC, HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, VISUAL STUDIO 2017, VISUAL STUDIO CODE, SQL SERVER 2014 LINQ TO SQL, BOOTSTRAP, ANGULARJS 1.5, API,

# PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

# Chicago Title Insurance Company, Chicago, IL

June 2010 - September 2017

### National Underwriter

Negotiated and drafted title insurance policies for commercial real estate clients across all 50 states. Managed large and complex multi-site transactions for properties ranging in value from \$1 million to \$200 million. Mentored and trained new underwriters and underwriting assistants. Coordinated closings with sales staff, escrow officers, and external customers under tight deadlines. Point person for clients concerns and questions related to their transactions. Resolved and/or negotiated terms to meet company standards and client needs.

# National Underwriting Associate,

**December 2011 – July 2014** 

Assisted underwriters through all phases of a commercial real estate transaction. Developed and maintained closing checklists. Served as Underwriting Team Member in new software initiative testing. Collaborated with and advised management and IT on its features and applicable functionality.

# National Business Coordinator,

June 2010 - December 2011

Opened and tracked a large volume of title commitment orders. Distributed title commitments to our customers using our proprietary software.

#### H&R Block, Brockton, MA

December 2009 - May 2010

#### **Accounts Payable Clerk**

Processed payment of invoices and employee time & expense reports per corporate guidelines. Consistently processed highest volume of invoices among employees holding the same position.

## One Stop Title, LLC, Cranston, RI

March 2008 - February 2010

#### Real Estate Paralegal

Managed residential real estate sales and refinances. Prepared legal documents, disbursement statements, processed checks and invoices. Provided bookkeeping services for the operation.

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

Northeastern University, Boston, MA

September 2003 - December 2007

BS in Criminal Justice Graduated Cum Laude

Boston University, Boston, MA

March 2008 - June 2008

Paralegal Certificate

**Anoka Ramsey Community College** 

April 2015 - December 2015

Financial Accounting, Managerial Accounting, Macro Economics, Micro Economics